Kevin Vo

Work Authorization: US Citizen Email: vodangkhoa@gmail.com



Objective

Seeking a senior technical position that leverages my past experiences building and launching innovative products.

Summary

Senior Engineer/Tech Lead with 10+ years of e-commerce experience across big companies and startups. Co-founded HipVan.com (raised 8 million USD, acquired by Bucketplace in November 2021). Spent 4+ years working at Amazon.com and AWS. Significant experience in Ruby on Rails, Python/Django/Flask, Javascript/Typescript, ReactJS, Java, and Amazon Web Services.

Experience

Senior Full Stack Engineer (Freelance), Self-Employed

San Francisco, CA — January 2019 - Present

Using Python, Django/Flask, Celery, MongoDB, TypeScript, Postgres, and ReactJS running on Docker, Kubernetes, and AWS.

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Postgres, Redis, Sidekiq, ReactJS, and Typescript running on Docker and Heroku.

Co-founder & CTO, Hipvan.com

Singapore — January 2013 - December 2018

Acquired by Bucketplace in November 2021.

Responsible for the product and engineering of HipVan.com. Leading iOS and Android applications, websites, and backend services. I coded/code reviewed/designed discussions 60% of my time.

Used Ruby on Rails, Amazon Web Services(EC2, S3, RDS, ElastiCache, ElasticSearch, Elastic Beanstalk, CloudFront, Lambda), Redis, PostgreSQL, ReactJS Native, JQuery, CSS/HTML.

Accomplishments

- Full ownership of Android and iOS apps, frontend and backend platform that shipped ~100K orders and ~20M in cumulative revenue.
- Designed and built backend products for reporting, inventory management, and order management systems.
- Led a team of 10+ developers.
- Launched hipvan.com, hipvan.com.my, and hipvan.us.
- Raised 10+ million USD.

Head of Development, Zalora Group

Singapore — January 2012 - December 2012

Accomplishments

- Built-up development teams for a regional development center for Zalora
 Group and Zalora Vietnam.
- Took ownership for Zalora Group codebase transfer from Berlin to Singapore.
- Worked with Marketing, Operation, and Customer Service teams to launch ZALORA Vietnam.

Software Engineer, Amazon.com

Seattle, WA — June 2007 - December 2011

Amazon Payments (payments.amazon.com)
Amazon Wireless Store (wireless.amazon.com)

Played a critical technical role in the delivery of Amazon Wireless store. Developed Front-end websites, developer tools, back-end services, caches, databases, message brokers, and related infrastructure.

Education

The University of Texas at Austin

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science - 2007

Interned at IBM, Intel, Expedia.com, and Indeed.com.

Skills

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Python, Flask, Java, Amazon Web Services(EC2, S3, RDS, ElastiCache, ElasticSearch, Elastic Beanstalk, CloudFront, Lambda), Redis, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Oracle, Jquery, CSS/HTML.

Work Authorization

US Citizen.